just getting started here I want to do
an introduction and kind of get a handle
on just what is Magellan course by way
of an overall introduction and I know
that for some of us we've been in this
now for about twelve weeks but we
haven't really talked about this
directly so when I think about that
question what is the Magellan course
what is the project
what is this voyage we've embarked on
the first thing I think of is that first
and foremost it's an experiment and this
experiment is ongoing and it's being
co-created by those who are
participating at many different levels
in many different scales if I ask myself
what kind of experiment is it I would
say perhaps to give it a color or a
flavor I would say it's an experiment in
what we might call post post modernism
or post post modern ways so it's
something new and emerging post post
modern ways of what we might say post
post modern ways of thinking post post
modern ways of being and this could also
mean being together not just an
individual aspect post post modern ways
because this is a course of learning and
we talked about the learning circle and
co-creating new and emerging type
learning so I think that would be a
start but I think that for me the
experiment really has a different
frontier because I think that this is
being done in many different forms and
so the frontier aspect of it I would say
and this is what gives the Magellan
voyage makes it a metaphor for us
because Magellan went into unknown
territories and that is it's an
experiment in not only post-postmodern
but a post dialectic engagement and what
I mean by that the possibility of a post
dialectic reasoning the possibility of
post dialectic language the possibility
of post dialectic modes of inquiry the
possibility of post dialectic discourse
and these are not only a frontier but
these are all have to be innovations
they have to be designed and co-created
so that's what I would say is the
frontier aspect of the magellan course
but I think that in addition to that
there's even another trajectory that I
envision and that trajectory has to do
with this notion of a process ontology
and the idea of an until logics and
these I think are really something
totally brand-new and the kind of
working hypothesis so in subsequent
videos I would like to talk about
exactly this what kind of experiments
leads it's post-postmodern ways that may
be already emerging and how do that
impacts ways of thinking being and
learning and these are things that we
might be seeing elsewhere and then to
look at this boundary this edge or this
frontier that the magellan course is
hoping to cross and what could it
possibly mean to have a host dialectic
or a trans rational kind of engagement
and how that would look like in terms of
the way we reason what types of
languages are needed what types of
enquiries need to be designed and what
types of discourse need to be co-created
so this could be a first video this area
could be a second video
with the different subsets gets a little
more complicated and then lastly this
whole notion of this trajectory where we
are going in terms of a process ontology
that would inform for example our
cosmology the really big ideas are
spirituality and how we make meaning for
example would be one of these big ideas
and then whether this notion of aanchal
objects can be facilitated and developed
and actually taught so to me that's what
the magellan course is all about both as
it arises today and looking at its
frontiers and its trajectory